var questionBank= [
    {
        question : 'aluminium',
        option : ['A','Al','Au','G'],
        answer : 'Al'
    },

    {
        question : 'argon',
        option : ['Ag','As','Ar','A'],
        answer : 'Ar'
    },

    {
        question : 'zwavel',
        option : ['S','Zw','Z','Za'],
        answer : 'S'
    },

    {
        question : 'zuurstof',
        option : ['Zu','Ox','Z','O'],
        answer : 'O'
    },

    {
        question : 'As',
        option : ['Argon','Arseen','Aluminius','Lithium'],
        answer : 'Arseen'
    },

    {
        question : 'Ba',
        option : ['Beryllium','Broom','Barium','Boor'],
        answer : 'Barium'
    },

    {
        question : 'Be',
        option : ['Barium','Fosfor','Fluor','Beryllium'],
        answer : 'Beryllium'
    },

    {
        question : 'Zn',
        option : ['Zilver','Zink','Goud','Neon'],
        answer : 'Zink'
    },

    {
        question : 'cadmium',
        option : ['Cd','Ca','Cm','R'],
        answer : 'Cd'
    },

    {
        question : 'Mg',
        option : ['Mangaan','Magnesium','Jood','Natrium'],
        answer : 'Magnesium'
    },

    {
        question : 'krypton',
        option : ['Kr','Hg','Cr','Y'],
        answer : 'Kr'
    },

    {
        question : 'Cl',
        option : ['Celycium','Chloor','Calium','Lood'],
        answer : 'Chloor'
    },

    {
        question : 'P',
        option : ['Fosfor','Platina','Xenon','Tin'],
        answer : 'Fosfor'
    },

    {
        question : 'K',
        option : ['Cadmium','Koper','Krypton','Kalium'],
        answer : 'Kalium'
    },

    {
        question : 'Br',
        option : ['Boor','Broom','Berylium','Barium'],
        answer : 'Broom'
    },

    {
        question : 'zilver',
        option : ['Zn','Hg','Ag','S'],
        answer : 'Ag'
    },

    {
        question : 'kobalt',
        option : ['Ko','K','Co','C'],
        answer : 'Co'
    },

    {
        question : 'Xe',
        option : ['Xenon','Neon','Stikstof','Nikkel'],
        answer : 'Xenon'
    },

    {
        question : 'Cu',
        option : ['Chloor','Calcium','Koper','Cadmium'],
        answer : 'Koper'
    },

    {
        question : 'ijzer',
        option : ['Ij','F','Iz','Fe'],
        answer : 'Fe'
    },

    {
        question : 'Mn',
        option : ['Mangaan','Magnesium','Platina','Nikkel'],
        answer : 'Mangaan'
    },

    {
        question : 'natrium',
        option : ['N','Nt','Na','E'],
        answer : 'Na'
    },

    {
        question : 'tin',
        option : ['Rn','T','Ti','Sn'],
        answer : 'Sn'
    },

    {
        question : 'Pb',
        option : ['Platina','Jood','Lood','Lithium'],
        answer : 'Lood'
    },

    {
        question : 'H',
        option : ['Waterstof','Helium','Ijzer','Goud'],
        answer : 'Waterstof'
    },

    {
        question : 'calcium',
        option : ['Ca','Cl','Ka','K'],
        answer : 'Ca'
    },

    {
        question : 'F',
        option : ['Fosfor','Ijzer','Zwavel','Fluor'],
        answer : 'Fluor'
    },

    {
        question : 'goud',
        option : ['Go','Au','Gl','Db'],
        answer : 'Au'
    },

    {
        question : 'Fe',
        option : ['Beryllium','Ijzer','Xenon','Zuurstof'],
        answer : 'Ijzer'
    },

    {
        question : 'I',
        option : ['Ijzer','Lood','Jood','Radon'],
        answer : 'Jood'
    },

    {
        question : 'Co',
        option : ['Kobalt','Chloor','Cadmium','Kalium'],
        answer : 'Kobalt'
    },

    {
        question : 'koolstof',
        option : ['H','O','Ko','C'],
        answer : 'C'
    },

    {
        question : 'Hg',
        option : ['Zilver','Ijzer','Zink','Kwik'],
        answer : 'Kwik'
    },

    {
        question : 'lithium',
        option : ['Li','Lt','Lh','Lu'],
        answer : 'Li'
    },
    {
        question : 'He',
        option : ['Berylium','Helium','Koolstof','Goud'],
        answer : 'Helium'
    },
    {
        question : 'berylium',
        option : ['Be', 'Ba','By','S'],
        answer : 'Be'
    },
    {
        question : 'magnesium',
        option : ['Ma','Mn','Gn','Mg'],
        answer : 'Mg'
    },
    {
        question : 'Si',
        option : ['Zink','Lood','Silicium','Koper'],
        answer : 'Silicium'
    },
    {
        question : 'uraan',
        option : ['U','Ur','Ua','Un'],
        answer : 'U'
    },
    {
        question : 'S',
        option : ['Fosfor','Zwavel','Silicium','Koolstof'],
        answer : 'Zwavel'
    },
    {
        question : 'lithium',
        option : ['Li','Lt','Lh','Lu'],
        answer : 'Li'
    },
    {
        question : 'Cr',
        option : ['Chroom','Chloor','Cadmium','Kalium'],
        answer : 'Chroom'
    },
    {
        question : 'Rn',
        option : ['Arseen','Argon','Platina','Radon'],
        answer : 'Radon'
    },
    {
        question : 'stikstof',
        option : ['St','N','Si','F'],
        answer : 'N'
    },
    {
        question : 'Li',
        option : ['Lithium','Platina','Koper','Lood'],
        answer : 'Lithium'
    },
    {
        question : 'lithium',
        option : ['Li','Lt','Lh','Lu'],
        answer : 'Li'
    },
    {
        question : 'Ne',
        option : ['Nikkel','Natrium','Neon','Argon'],
        answer : 'Ne'
    },
    {
        question : 'platina',
        option : ['Pl','Pa','P','Pt'],
        answer : 'Pt'
    },
    {
        question : 'silicium',
        option : ['Si','S','F','Ar'],
        answer : 'Si'
    },
    {
        question : 'B',
        option : ['Broom','Boor','Barium','Berylium'],
        answer : 'Boor'
    },
    {
        question : 'Ca',
        option : ['Cadmium','Kalium','Calcium','Barium'],
        answer : 'Calcium'
    },
    {
        question : 'mangaan',
        option : ['Ma','Mn','Mg','M'],
        answer : 'Mn'
    },
    {
        question : 'Pb',
        option : ['Lood','Jood','Kwik','Berylium'],
        answer : 'Lood'
    },
    {
        question : 'O',
        option : ['Koolstof','Waterstof','Mangaan','Zuurstof'],
        answer : 'Zuurstof'
    },
    {
        question : 'zink',
        option : ['Z','Sn','Zn','L'],
        answer : 'Zn'
    },
    {
        question : 'Ag',
        option : ['Kwik','Zilver','Goud','Argon'],
        answer : 'Zilver'
    },
    {
        question : 'xenon',
        option : ['X','Xn','Xe','E'],
        answer : 'Xe'
    },
    {
        question : 'waterstof',
        option : ['H','W','Ws','Lu'],
        answer : 'H'
    },
    {
        question : 'U',
        option : ['Waterstof','Lithium','Tin','Uraan'],
        answer : 'Uraan'
    },
    {
        question : 'Sn',
        option : ['Tin','Zink','Silicium','Lithium'],
        answer : 'Tin'
    },
    {
        question : 'Al',
        option : ['Argon','Aluminium','Arseen','Radon'],
        answer : 'Aluminium'
    },
    {
        question : 'arseen',
        option : ['As','Ar','Ra','Ae'],
        answer : 'As'
    },
    {
        question : 'C',
        option : ['Koolstof','Waterstof','Zuurstof','Koper'],
        answer : 'Koolstof'
    },
    {
        question : 'N',
        option : ['Nikkel','Neon','Stikstof','Tin'],
        answer : 'Stikstof'
    },
    {
        question : 'radon',
        option : ['Rn','As','Ra','Ad'],
        answer : 'Rn'
    },
    {
        question : 'Pt',
        option : ['Aluminium','Platina','Stikstof','Argon'],
        answer : 'Platina'
    },
    {
        question : 'nikkel',
        option : ['N','Ne','Nk','Ni'],
        answer : 'Ni'
    },
    {
        question : 'neon',
        option : ['Ni','Nk','Ne','N'],
        answer : 'Ne'
    },
    {
        question : 'Na',
        option : ['Natrium','Barium','Neon','Nikkel'],
        answer : 'Natrium'
    },
    {
        question : 'kwik',
        option : ['K','Ag','Hg','Sn'],
        answer : 'Hg'
    },
    {
        question : 'Kr',
        option : ['Krypton','Kalium','Kobalt','Cadmium'],
        answer : 'Krypton'
    },
    {
        question : 'Ni',
        option : ['Neon','Natrium','Krypton','Nikkel'],
        answer : 'Nikkel'
    },
    {
        question : 'koper',
        option : ['Ko','Co','Kp','Cu'],
        answer : 'Cu'
    },
    {
        question : 'kalium',
        option : ['Ca','Ka','Li','K'],
        answer : 'K'
    },
    {
        question : 'jood',
        option : ['Jo','I','J','Cu'],
        answer : 'I'
    },
    {
        question : 'helium',
        option : ['He','H','Hl','Hi'],
        answer : 'He'
    },
    {
        question : 'Au',
        option : ['Lood','Krypton','Zink','Goud'],
        answer : 'Goud'
    },
    {
        question : 'fosfor',
        option : ['F','Fo','P','Fs'],
        answer : 'P'
    },
    {
        question : 'fluor',
        option : ['Fs','P','Fo','F'],
        answer : 'F'
    },
    {
        question : 'chroom',
        option : ['Cr','Ch','Co','K'],
        answer : 'Cr'
    },
    {
        question : 'chloor',
        option : ['Ch','Cl','Co','K'],
        answer : 'Cl'
    },
    {
        question : 'Cd',
        option : ['Calcium','Kalium','Kwik','Cadmium'],
        answer : 'Cadmium'
    },
    {
        question : 'broom',
        option : ['B','Br','Bm','Li'],
        answer : 'Br'
    },
    {
        question : 'boor',
        option : ['B','Bo','Br','C'],
        answer : 'B'
    },
    {
        question : 'barium',
        option : ['B','Br','Bo','Ba'],
        answer : 'Ba'
    },
    {
        question : 'Ar',
        option : ['Arseen','Radon','Argon','Aluminium'],
        answer : 'Argon'
    },

    
]

var question= document.getElementById('question');
var quizContainer= document.getElementById('quiz-container');
var scorecard= document.getElementById('scorecard');
var option0= document.getElementById('option0');
var option1= document.getElementById('option1');
var option2= document.getElementById('option2');
var option3= document.getElementById('option3');
var next= document.querySelector('.next');
var points= document.getElementById('score');
var span= document.querySelectorAll('span');
var i=0;
var score= 0;

//function to display questions
function displayQuestion(){
    for(var a=0;a<span.length;a++){
        span[a].style.background='none';
    }
    question.innerHTML= (i+1)+'. '+questionBank[i].question;
    option0.innerHTML= questionBank[i].option[0];
    option1.innerHTML= questionBank[i].option[1];
    option2.innerHTML= questionBank[i].option[2];
    option3.innerHTML= questionBank[i].option[3];
    stat.innerHTML= "Question"+' '+(i+1)+' '+'of'+' '+questionBank.length;
}

//function to calculate scores
function calcScore(e){
    if(e.innerHTML===questionBank[i].answer && score<questionBank.length)
    {
        score= score+1;
        document.getElementById(e.id).style.background= 'limegreen';
    }
    else{
        document.getElementById(e.id).style.background= 'tomato';
    }
    setTimeout(nextQuestion,300);
}

//function to display next question
function nextQuestion(){
    if(i<questionBank.length-1)
    {
        i=i+1;
        displayQuestion();
    }
    else{
        points.innerHTML= score+ '/'+ questionBank.length;
        quizContainer.style.display= 'none';
        scoreboard.style.display= 'block'
    }
}

//click events to next button
next.addEventListener('click',nextQuestion);

//Back to Quiz button event
function backToQuiz(){
    location.reload();
}

//function to check Answers
function checkAnswer(){
    var answerBank= document.getElementById('answerBank');
    var answers= document.getElementById('answers');
    answerBank.style.display= 'block';
    scoreboard.style.display= 'none';
    for(var a=0;a<questionBank.length;a++)
    {
        var list= document.createElement('li');
        list.innerHTML= questionBank[a].answer;
        answers.appendChild(list);
    }
}


displayQuestion();
